# 看着啊 排好了
Look at this, line them up.
# 立着
Stand here.
# 还得让它立着
We need to make it stand.
# 全是立的
They are all standing on their 'feet'
# 看 剔小腿
See, let's prepare the drumstick.
# 顺着这骨子的边剌一刀
Make a incision along the bone
# 斩一刀
Cut through
# 利索
Clean through.
# 牙签骨在这儿呢
Notice there's a little bone on the side (fibula)
# 这上面小腿有筋 我们要排排刀
There are some tendons in the drumstick, we need to score it.
# 然后排完再用刀尖 把筋彻底切断
and use the tip of the knife to break the tendon
# 一切断以后下锅煎 它就不会回来了
So that it won't curl when we sear it.
# 立着
Stand up!
# 适合快餐
Really good for fast food.
# 到时候戴一花儿 好看
We'll decorate with 'flower' at the end.
# 看着啊排好了 立着
Line them up, stand them up.
# 还得让它立着
# 看着啊 全是立的
Look they are all standing!
# 好 咱们开始上浆了 码味
OK, let's marinate it now.
# 酱油
Soy sauce,
# 这是老抽 冰糖老抽
dark soy sauce (for color)
# 白胡椒粉
ground white pepper
# 少来盐 因为一会还有炒黑椒汁
Just a little salt. Because we will make some pepper sauce later.
# 淀粉
Corn starch
# 搁鸡蛋么 搁鸡蛋
Eggs? Sure
# （半个）全蛋 多了还不好
Half an egg, not too much
# 多了出啰嗦了
(if too much) it will be soupy
# 黄酒
Huangjiu cooking wine
# 这跟我们平时上浆的意思是一样的
Just like the regular marinade
# 马上好了 切点小料
Almost ready, let's get some condiments.
# 大爷每天就是老菜
Da Ye always does these traditional dishes,
# 教啊教啊 还切呢
He teaches a lot. He even demonstrates knife skills!
# 跟里边腌一下（葱段姜片）
Green onion and ginger, into the marinade
# 二伯帮着搁点香油
Some sesame oil please, Er Bai
# 香油必须得搁 香油去腥啊
Sesame oil is a must, it drives away the gaminess
# 腌十分钟到十五分钟
Marinade the chicken for 10-15 minutes
# 切料头齐了
Now the condiments: green onion, ginger, garlic
# 葱姜蒜 青红辣椒 来点葱头
Red/green and some shallots.
# 下面呢 关键点
Now the important part:
# 炒胡椒 咱都得现制
Toast the black pepper
# 黑胡椒
Black pepper
# 黑胡椒比白胡椒味重
Black pepper has a heavier flavour than white pepper
# 这个鸡就是任何味都好接触
Chicken really goes well with all flavour profiles,
# 柠檬的 番茄的 鱼香的
lemony, tomato-ey, fish flavoured,
# 香辣的 香草的 宫保的
hot, herbal, KongPao, etc
# 好了 这个咱给擀了
Ready now, let's ground the pepper
# 黑胡椒的味道我觉得要比白胡椒要香
I think black pepper is more fragrant than white pepper
# 香味扑鼻 行了给拿一小碗
Sure does. Now, a small bowl
# 二伯 给来点油 好了
Er Bai, add some oil
# 这个料就算备完了
Preparation is done
# 油温六成热
Maintain oil temp at around 180C (356F)
# 煎到两面焦黄
Sear until golden brown on both sides
# 煎的比炸的还要香 煎炸
It's more flavourful to sear, than to fry
# 因为它还没有完全熟透
No need to cook it through,
# （主要是让）外面焦黄
just give it some colour and crust
# 这就完事了
Done.
# 黑胡椒
black pepper...
# 葱姜蒜
Green onion, ginger, garlic
# 洋葱
Onion
# 香味就这么出来了
Wow that smell!
# 这黑胡椒的味还真挺好闻的
This black pepper smells really good.
# 酱油
Soy sauce
# 你看这广东菜就这样
It's how Cantonese cooking should be
# 黄酒 香味就顺着锅边就出来了
Cooking wine, pour in on the side of the wok
# 这就叫烹
Cooking off the alcohol.
# 搁点蚝油 得使劲 好了
Some oyster sauce in.
# 名副其实的大菜
A real banquet dish
# 你看过去宴会这菜 怎么样小亮
How was it, they used to serve it on banquets
# 来点白糖 没有白糖提不了鲜
Sugar. Without sugar, the dish is lack of umami taste
# 这肯定也是上位菜的 对
It was definitely a main dish back then. - Yes.
# 让它迅速成熟
Let it cook.
# 王朝辉 锡纸花 这个没锡纸花还真不好看
Zhaohui! Aluminium foil flower, really needs it
# 好了 熟了
Done!
# 这个味浓郁
That's some serious smell!
# 出锅了
Take it out!
# 怎么样这味 我特喜欢黑胡椒这味
How is it, I really like the black pepper taste.
# （放青红椒丁）
(Add in the diced green/red pepper)
# 给点香油
A touch of sesame oil
# 青红椒都搁进来了啊
Green and red pepper all in?
# 浇汁
Pour it on top.
# 齐活了
Nearly done!
# 就差锡纸了 王朝辉
Waiting for the foil, Zhaohui!
# 亮子 过去这是个老菜
Liang zi, It's a traditional dish.
# 过去的商店专门有做这花儿的
There were some stores selling this foil-made flower
# 各种颜色 粉的红的
in all colours, pink, red, etc
# 它叫什么 叫炸鸡腿戴花
It's called the "flowers for fried chicken"
# 专门为这道菜准备的
Specifically prepared for this dish.
# 它为了什么 要什么意思呢
But why we need the flower?
# 客人吃的时候 拿起来
When you eating, pick up,
# 不烫手 手里还没油
it wouldn't be too hot, nor oily.
# 花上有一小筒 这样套在鸡腿里边
You wrap around like this.
# 还有一个网油包鸡腿
There's another dish, caul fat wrapped drumstick
# 那也是要戴花的
it needs the flower too.
# 所以这道菜是一个传统的老菜
It's a traditional dish.
# 今天我们就用现场的锡纸
Today we use foil we have here
# 简洁的做了一个小花
to make a simple foil flower.
# 也很好看 好了 我就等着吃了
Looks nice. Good, now I'm waiting to eat.
# 二伯 给后生给后生
Er Bai, child first
# 这不合适 后生后生
Nah, that's inappropriate!
# 那我就不客气了 不用客气
Sure, I'll eat then.
# 那你还客气 知道你爱吃肉
Just eat, I know you like meat
# 黑胡椒的辣特别好吃
I really like the heat from the pepper
# 这个菜非常有传承的意义
It's a lineage you know
# 是不是小亮
# 对不对 你再尝一口 你吃了三块了
Correct? Man, you ate three pieces already
# 很下饭啊
It's really good
# 这口菜要配上热米饭 绝了
Even better with hot rice
# 烫嘴的热米饭 好吃
# 谢谢二伯 谢谢亮子
Thanks Er Bai, Liangzi!
# 自我也总结一下
Let me summarize myself.
# 因为我们现场还是有一些局限性
We are still kinda limited here,
# 按道理这黑椒汁 从传统的技艺方法
traditionally this black pepper sauce needs to cook longer in the pan
# 应该好好的在锅里多熬一会儿
# 过去熬的方法得炒
and with some leek oil and butter
# 炒这葱头油 搁点黄油
and with some green onion oil and butter
# 让它味儿更释放的多一些
to further bring up its flavour
# 现在表面上有点辣
It's a bit spicy on the skin
# 实际上完全的黑椒汁
Actually the black pepper flavour
# 没完全释放出来 得熬一会
doesn't release completely. Need to cook for a bit longer.
# 然后我们再进行烹制
So that we start cooking afterwards,
# 但是我们现场程序要快
But here we demonstrate a quicker way,
# 让网友掌握的简单实用
more doable at home
# 这味道 味道还可以 就好
The flavour, not as good as in restaurants, but will do at home
# 家庭版
A homemade version!
# 咱们街道办事处 岚马 就问说
Someone on our street office, Lan Ma, asked
# 看了几个方子
Seeing a few of recipes,
# 清汤腩做的还是一般般
my clear broth braised brisket are still ordinary.
# 香料控制的还行
The herb and spices are about right,
# 但是肉香感觉老是不够
but the meaty flavour are not strong enough.
# 不知道有什么小窍门
Is there any tricks
# 可以提升
to help me improve?
# 清汤腩是一个人吗
Qing Tang Nan, is that a person??
# 清汤牛腩
Oh, clear broth braised brisket.
# 我们买好的牛腩
Buy the good quality beef brisket
# 买回来以后
When you bring it back
# 像切红烧肉的这种肉块
Chop up the beef into square cubes, like braised pork belly.
# 是吧
Right?
# 把它切好了
After you chop it,
# 切好了以后我们要冲水
run it under water
# 然后我们放到一个锅里头
Then put it in a big pot
# 水宽一点
add enough water
# 然后烧开 凉水下锅
cold water, then bring it to a boil
# 不加任何东西
No need to add anything else.
# 然后它开了以后
Once it boils,
# 尤其在开（锅）这一瞬间
especially when it's just about to boil
# 一定要把血沫处理干净
Skim off all the scum
# 洗完了赶快捞到盆里头
take it out right after you wash it
# 锅里还接着放凉水
put in a fresh pot of cold water
# 把牛肉再（放）回到锅里
put the beef back in the pot.
# 放一根胡萝卜 整根的
Add a whole carrot,
# 放一个葱头 一切两开
an onion split in half
# 放上一根芹菜
and a piece of celery.
# 开锅
Bring it to a boil
# 可能还会有浮沫
there may still some scum
# 把这浮沫打咯
Skim them off
# 牛肉它不吃花椒
It is hard for beef to absorb Szechuan pepper flavour
# 就放两个大料
just add two star anises,
# 放一片香叶
and one bay leaf
# 放几粒小茴香
a couple of fennel seeds,
# 小火慢炖
simmer it, low and slow
# 半小时左右
for around half an hour
# 如果说着急的话
If you are in a hurry,
# 放到高压锅里边
you can use a pressure cooker as well.
# 高压锅现在我们有智能键
Some pressure cooker has "smart" preset mode,
# 炖牛肉羊肉
use the beef/lamb stew mode
# 一按 二十分钟
press the button, for like 20 minutes
# 就ok了
it'd be ready
# 放了气  出了锅
once you take it out,
# （放）黄酒 放点姜
add some cooking wine and ginger
# 不加任何东西 也不加盐
Don't need to add anything. No salt.
# 不要放葱了
No more green onion.